Smith Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Photographs, circa 1845-1934, Series 6:; (Box 6 and Black Cabinet; 0.4 linear ft.)
  Photographs included ambrotypes, daguerreotypes, and tintypes, along with glass negatives and a small number of original prints. Although the original ambrotypes, daguerreotypes, and tintypes were not microfilmed, copy negatives and prints have been produced from the glass negatives and are filed within the collection. The majority of folders contain the original photograph in addition to a copy negative and/or copy print.
  This series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  6.1: People, circa 1845-1919
  6.2: Artwork, undated
  6.3: Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1870-1934
  Although referenced as folder titles, cased photographs are stored separately. Copy prints are found within the numbered boxes and folders and the originals are filed in the "black cabinet".
  - People, circa 1845-1919, 6.1:
    Among the photographs of people are group and individual portraits of Russell and Mary Priscilla Smith, and their children Xanthus and Mary. There are also images of Russell's uncle, granddaughter, and sister, along with several unidentified individuals.
    - Smith Family (Box 6 (hol))
      - Salt Paper Print: Russell, Mary Priscilla, and Mary Smith attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1857, undated, (Reel 2062: 33) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 1)
      - Russell and Mary Priscilla Smith with daughter Mary, and Margaret Russell Smith (sister of Russell Smith) attributed to Xanthus Smith, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 2)
    - Andrew Smith (uncle of Russell Smith): Tintype by Xanthus Smith, circa 1865 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 3)
    - George Russell Smith: see Xanthus Russell Smith, Jr. and George Russell Smith (Box 6 (hol))
    - Margaret Russell Smith: see Smith Family (Box 6 (hol))
    - Mary Binder Smith (Mrs. Xanthus Smith): Hand Tinted Photograph, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 4)
    - Mary Priscilla Smith (see also Smith Family and Russell Smith) (Box 6 (hol))
      - Ambrotype Copy Print, circa 1860 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 5)
      - Daguerreotypes Copy Prints, circa 1845-1850s, (2 items) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 6)
      - Tintype Copy Print attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1864 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 7)
    - Mary Smith (Box 6 (hol))
      - Ambrotypes Copy Prints, 1 attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1850s, circa 1865 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 8)
      - Daguerreotype Copy Prints, circa 1850s (Box 6 (hol), Folder 9)
      - Tintype Copy Print, attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1865, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 10)
    - Russell Smith (Box 6 (hol))
      - Portraits (Box 6 (hol))
        - Ambrotype Copy Print, circa 1858 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 11)
        - Carte de Visite, undated, (Reel 2062: 7) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 12)
        - Daguerreotype Copy Print, circa 1848 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 13)
        - Glass Negatives, circa 1890-1895, undated, (Reel 2062: 15-20) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 14)
      - In Studio, Glass Negative, undated, (Reel 2062: 22) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 15)
      - With Grandaughter "Polly" (Mary Russell Smith, daughter of Xanthus) (Box 6 (hol))
        - Ambrotype Copy Print, circa 1880s (Box 6 (hol), Folder 16)
        - Glass Negatives, circa 1885-1890, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 17)
      - With Mary Priscilla Smith, Stereo Tintype, attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1870 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 18)
    - Xanthus Smith (Box 6 (hol))
      - Ambrotypes Copy Prints, circa 1855 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 19)
      - Daguerreotype Copy Print, circa 1855 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 20)
      - Glass Plate Negative, undated, (Reel 2062: 8) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 21)
      - Glass Plate Negative, Xanthus in Civil War Uniform, circa 1863, (Reel 2062: 27) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 22)
    - Xanthus Smith, Jr., and George Russell Smith (sons of Xanthus and Mary Binder Smith), by Bachrach, 1919, (Reel 2062: 44-45) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 23)
    - Unidentified Individuals (Box 6 (hol))
      - Couples, Ambrotype, Copy Prints circa 1865 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 24)
      - Couples, Tintype, Copy Printscirca 1856 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 25)
      - Women, Cartes de Visit, undated, (Reel 2062: 32, 34) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 26)
    - Smith Family, Ambrotype: Russell and Mary Priscilla Smith with daughter Mary, and Margaret Russell Smith (sister of Russell Smith) attributed to Xanthus Smith, undated, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 1)
    - Andrew Smith (uncle of Russell Smith): Tintype by Xanthus Smith, circa 1865, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 2)
    - Mary Binder Smith (Mrs. Xanthus Smith): Hand Tinted Photograph, undated, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 3)
    - Mary Priscilla Smith (Box Blk. Cab. 1)
      - Ambrotype, circa 1860, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 4)
      - Daguerreotypes, circa 1845-1850s, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 5)
      - Tintype attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1864, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 6)
    - Mary Smith (Box Blk. Cab. 1)
      - Ambrotypes, 1 attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1850s, circa 1865, (copy prints in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 7)
      - Daguerreotype, circa 1850s, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 8)
      - Tintype, attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1865, undated, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 9)
    - Russell Smith (Box Blk. Cab. 1)
      - Portraits, Ambrotype, circa 1858, (copy prints in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 10)
      - Portraits, Daguerreotype, circa 1848, (copy prints in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 11)
      - With Grandaughter "Polly," Ambrotype, circa 1880s, (copy prints in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 12)
      - With Mary Priscilla Smith, Stereo Tintype, attributed to Xanthus Smith, circa 1870, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 13)
    - Xanthus Smith (Box Blk. Cab. 1)
      - Ambrotypes, circa 1855, (copy prints in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 14)
      - Daguerreotype, circa 1855, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified Individuals (Box Blk. Cab. 1)
      - Couples, Ambrotype, circa 1865, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 16)
      - Couples, Tintype, circa 1856, (copy print in Box 6) (Box Blk. Cab. 1, Folder 17)
  - Artwork, undated, 6.2:
    Photographs of artwork are by Russell Smith, Xanthus Smith, and other artists. The photograph of artwork by Russell Smith is of a printed reproduction incorrectly described as being by W.T.R. Smith. Photographs of artwork by Xanthus Smith consist of 17 glass negatives without copy prints.
    - By Russell Smith, "Robert Morris by W.T.R. Smith 1831," undated, (Reel 2062: 42-43) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 27)
    - By Xanthus Smith, "Copies of Wash Drawings of Battle Pieces - Copies of X. S. wash drawings of Farragut's naval battles Mississippi - Mobil - Kearsarge and Alabama," undated, (2 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 28-29)
    - By Other Artists - Portraits of Jacob Krips (Smith ancestor) and Unidentified Individuals, undated, (Reel 2062: 46-52) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1870-1934, 6.3:
    - Landscapes - Unidentified Panorama and Two Aerial Views of the Smith Home, 1934, undated, (Reel 2062: 38, 53-56) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 31)
    - "Reading Terminal in Progress, X. S. Photo," circa 1892, (Reel 2062: 40) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 32)
    - Three Unidentified Men with Steam Engine (cyanotype by Xanthus Smith, with copy negative and copy print), circa 1870, undated, (Reel 2062: 41) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 33)